<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amazon on Martin Liu's Blog</title><link>https://martinliu.cn/tags/amazon/</link><description>Recent content in Amazon on Martin Liu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 21:44:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martinliu.cn/tags/amazon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Top10全球排名前十的云计算公司</title><link>https://martinliu.cn/2013/05/07/top10e585a8e79083e68e92e5908de5898de58d81e79a84e4ba91e8aea1e7ae97e585ace58fb8/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 02:31:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinliu.cn/2013/05/07/top10e585a8e79083e68e92e5908de5898de58d81e79a84e4ba91e8aea1e7ae97e585ace58fb8/</guid><description>&lt;p>来自  &lt;a class="link" href="http://www.intelligenthq.com/uncategorized/top-10-cloud-computing-companies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://www.intelligenthq.com/uncategorized/top-10-cloud-computing-companies/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Citrix 榜上有名排名第三，这就是我看好 CloudStack 一年多的回报，国内 CloudStack 目前看还没有什么生机，希望能早点发展起来。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We all know change is constant, especially in technology. Look at Toshiba, a world leader and innovator in high technology. This week, the company made an interesting move and announced the opening of Toshiba’s first datacenter in Europe, located in France.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Toshiba Cloud &amp;amp; Solutions Division is directed at professional markets, public and private-sector companies, and entities within the Toshiba Group. The creation of this datacenter is in line with the Group’s goal of accompanying its clients right from the design of IT products and solutions through to hosting related services tailored to specific needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The datacenter also hosts firms located in other regions, illustrating Toshiba’s broader ambitions. &lt;a class="link" href="http://www.intelligenthq.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Cloud-Computing.jpeg" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>&lt;img src="http://www.intelligenthq.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Cloud-Computing-180x110.jpg"
loading="lazy"
>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“&lt;em>Developing this first datacenter in Rhône-Alpes highlights the importance of the Grand Lyon project for Toshiba and embodies the group’s investment in the development of its Cloud offering&lt;/em>,&lt;em>”&lt;/em>  explains Philippe Hartmanshenn, Managing Director of Toshiba Systèmes France’s Cloud &amp;amp; Solutions Division.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“&lt;em>This allows us to move both internal and external client resources and services offsite to our high-security servers – located in France. We also plan to use the datacenter to develop and integrate business solutions for our clients from every sector.”&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>__I felt the need to highlight this as it shows the importance of the cloud, as an important tool to innovation regardless of industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="http://www.intelligenthq.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/BeFunky_CloudComputingImage.jpg.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>&lt;img src="http://www.intelligenthq.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/BeFunky_CloudComputingImage.jpg.jpg"
loading="lazy"
>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So who are the Top 10 players of cloud computing services that has been making waves recently?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1. Google&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Google Cloud is the approach of Google to provide enterprise solutions to companies. Google Cloud Platform allows you to build applications and websites, store and analyze data on Google’s infrastructure. Companies can build websites, applications and service on this platform. Apart from these Google also offers Google Apps for businesses, which is now growing. Google has recently unveiled a “patent pledge” that it hopes will shield cloud software and big data developers from  litigation. The pledge, which is like a non-aggression pact, covers ten patents related to Google’s MapReduce technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2. Microsoft&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The foundations of the Cloud OS are Windows Server and Windows Azure, complemented by the full breadth of our technology solutions, such as SQL Server, System Center and Visual Studio. Together, these technologies provide one consistent platform for infrastructure, apps and data that can span your datacenter, service provider datacenters, and the Microsoft public cloud.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>3. Citrix&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Citrix Cloud Platform provides the latest and most advanced open source software platform to build highly scalable and reliable cloud computing environments. Citrix offers three form of cloud computing – Hosted public cloud, Hosted private cloud and On-premise private cloud; Recently as per Info-Tech Research Group, Citrix Cloud platform is announced the Champion in Cloud Management Vendor Landscape. Citrix recently announced the availability of CloudPortal™ Business Manager 2.0, a cloud services delivery platform that enables enterprises and service providers to unify the commerce, user management, provisioning and operational aspects of a cloud into a single cloud interface for delivering anything as a service (XaaS).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**4. Joyent
**
San Francisco infrastructure-as-a-service provider, Joyent is the high-performance cloud infrastructure company, offering the only solution specifically built to power real-time web and mobile applications. Recently with the combined efforts of Joyent and Xeround (a cloud database company), Joyent customers can now access free and highly available with zero management MYSQL database. Xeround relational database is only available for Joyent Cloud platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>**5. CenturyLink
**
CenturyLink, 3rd largest telecommunication company in USA and an established leader in providing networking solutions and cloud hosting services. CenturyLink recently announced that it’s providing 100 Gigabyte per sec (Gbps) networking solutions and will continue to provide best cloud infrastructure and IT hosting solutions. Savvis, a subsidiary of CenturyLink has collaborated with VMware Cloud Applications Marketplace to provide wide variety of applications packages to its clients from various software and hardware vendors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>6. Amazon&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amazon EC2 is an Infrastructure as a Service Cloud Computing Platform provided by Amazon Web Services (AWS), which allows users to provision or deletion of virtual computers. Amazon is one of the true innovators in Web-based computing, offering pay-as-you-go access to virtual servers and data storage space. Recently Amazon announced AWS CloudHSM, a new service enabling customers to increase data security and meet compliance requirements by using dedicated Hardware Security Module (HSM) appliances within the AWS Cloud. The CloudHSM service allows customers to securely generate, store and manage cryptographic keys used for data encryption in a way that keys are accessible only by the customer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>7. IBM&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IBM Smart Cloud – IBM’s enterprise-class public cloud infrastructure-as-a-service (IaaS)delivers secure and scalable hosted IT infrastructure with on-demand access to virtual server and storage resources. BM recently announced global availability for its cloud service on five continents—plus a new center opening in Spain—based on its industry-leading sourcing business to host SAP applications and other core operations. Now clients can turn to cloud computing for enterprise applications while reducing the overall cost of IT and at the same time, expanding online access and investing in innovative analytics, social business and mobile computing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>8. Salesforce&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Salesforce.com’s CRM solution is broken down into several broad categories: Sales Cloud, Service Cloud, Data Cloud, Collaboration Cloud and Custom Cloud. Saleforce is aiming be the first cloud computing company to hit the $4 billion annual revenue by 2014 and you can assume this from its 3rd quarter earnings. Salesforce will concentrate on social media, mobile computing and real time in a project it refers to as Cloud 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>9. Rackspace&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rackspace, an open cloud company is delivering enterprise-level hosting services to businesses of all sizes and kinds around the world since 1998 and have grown to serve more than 190,000 customers. Rackspace integrates the industry’s best technologies for each customer’s specific need and delivers it as a service via its commitment to fanatical support. Rackspace recently opened the doors to its Open Cloud Academy by launching a pilot training program. The Open Cloud Academy is an educational program designed to provide students with affordable IT certifications, specifically around open cloud technologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>10. Verizon Terremark&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Verizon started its cloud computing services as a part of its enterprise solutions. Its infrastructure services have helped many of the world’s top enterprises improve IT performance and evolve business processes. Verizon Terremark sets the standard for IT deployments with advanced infrastructure and managed service offerings that deliver the scale, security, and reliability necessary to meet the demanding requirements of enterprises and governments around the world. Terremark launched its Enterprise Cloud Private Edition a single-tenant environment and its OS- and network-agnostic strategy shows the telco cloud understands the value of accessibility and integration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>从云计算联想到第一代电脑系统</title><link>https://martinliu.cn/2009/01/19/e4bb8ee4ba91e8aea1e7ae97e88194e683b3e588b0e7acace4b880e4bba3e794b5e88491e7b3bbe7bb9f/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 07:32:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinliu.cn/2009/01/19/e4bb8ee4ba91e8aea1e7ae97e88194e683b3e588b0e7acace4b880e4bba3e794b5e88491e7b3bbe7bb9f/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.cartoonstock.com/newscartoons/cartoonists/ato/lowres/aton964l.jpg"
loading="lazy"
>记得以前看过一本描写 Bill Gets 的书，他上中学的时候，在河滨中心通过一个远程终端，连接到某大学的计算机系统，输入程序代码，并且得到代码在远程电脑系统中的输出，输出好像是在屏幕上出现的，或从打印机上输出的。我基本上忘了那电脑系统的名称，不过它的特点基本上是这样的：当时电脑系统很少，可能全世界上也没有多少台功能全面的电脑；用户使用的特别像是一种计算服务，由于终端设备根本没有技术能力，当时还没有个人电脑；接入方式根本不是 tcp/ip 更不是 internet，当时还没 internet。在学习了云计算的一些概念之后，我迷惑了，这个时尚的技术，怎么越看越眼熟啊。&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->IBM 的主机系统可谓是当今电脑世界的恐龙化石级产品，他是一个活化石基本的技术，在经历了开放系统时代之后，我们即将进入云计算时代，我总感觉云计算是一种技术路线的复古。主机系统和第一代电脑系统最相似，区别是可以通过 TCP/ip 网络，和开放系统通信了。最为一种新兴起的技术，我试图 follow &lt;a class="link" href="http://www.johnmwillis.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://www.johnmwillis.com/&lt;/a>来学习云计算，遗憾的是从 08 年初以来并没有仔细听他所有的 colud cafe；这个老兄在把 blog 改名为 IT Management and Cloud Blog，真可谓是一高产的 blogger，这哥们每天能发四五个 post，强啊。最近找时间&lt;a class="link" href="http://media.libsyn.com/media/botchagalupe/cafe27.mp3" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>听了一段 cloud cafe&lt;/a>，我发现到目前为止还没有一个能让大多数人都认同的云计算的概念，基本上对云计算的感念方面有两道三种说法。可以看看 &lt;a class="link" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloud_computing" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloud_computing&lt;/a> 参考这上面的说法也只能有一个模糊的感觉。&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->看看电脑技术打发展历程：最早的电脑系统，主机系统，开放系统，群集，网格，云计算。前一段时间看过一个非常抢眼的标题“以后世界上将只有 5 台电脑”。SaaS 是一个比较火热的和云计算相关的技术，我认为它像是在 web2.0 发展到一定阶段后 Web 应用的一个发展，这方面的强者为 salesforce 之流。Google 和 Salesforce 不同的是，Google 提供网上 office 套件的同时，还开发他的平台，并提供与之配套的 SDK。Amazon 不提供应用也没有 SDK，他只提供平台，平台上包括基本的计算和存储服务。Google 和 Amazon 说起来算是基础架构作为一种服务。抛开云计算本身不谈，用户使用和访问的方式并没有发生变化，在任何一个 web 浏览器存在的地方都能使用或者管理到云计算。客户端的计算和存储能力再次此退化到零，这不能说不是计算机技术发展的返祖现象吧！哈哈～～我也快糊涂了！&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>