<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chrome on Martin Liu's Blog</title><link>https://martinliu.cn/tags/chrome/</link><description>Recent content in Chrome on Martin Liu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 21:44:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martinliu.cn/tags/chrome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What's Google Chrome OS</title><link>https://martinliu.cn/2009/11/23/whats-google-chrome-os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 04:38:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinliu.cn/2009/11/23/whats-google-chrome-os/</guid><description>&lt;p>看完这个视频之后，还是没搞清楚：它到是一个快速的浏览器，还是一个快速启动的 OS 加浏览器，如果它仍然需要 OS 的话，那么它不过是一个 Redesigned 的 OS+操作系统。说白了就是瘦客户端加肥浏览器的组合吧！&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->您用 Google 的浏览器么？我用了一次就删除了，至今没有尝试装 Google 的操作系统。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Do you like Chrome?</title><link>https://martinliu.cn/2008/09/05/do-you-like-chrome/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 05:10:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinliu.cn/2008/09/05/do-you-like-chrome/</guid><description>&lt;p>Peoples always love whatever Google&amp;rsquo;s invention, I am using Gmail and GTalk every day too. But I think I couldn&amp;rsquo;t say I like google anytime. That&amp;rsquo;s just because Chrome. It was installed on my laptop yesterday. I&amp;rsquo;m trying it out when I access any of my google services (Gmail, Reader, Doc, etc&amp;hellip;). There are some App shortcuts are already on my XP deskdtop.  Base on one day experience of Chrome, I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about reasons I don&amp;rsquo;t like Chrome. I has not tested it too much at present, just few comments below:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;img src="http://blogs.zdnet.com/perlow/images/chrome-constrictor.jpg"
loading="lazy"
>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Chrome&amp;rsquo;s Name:&lt;/strong> I still do not figure out how to pronounce this word, someone says it sounds like a man perfume; I do thinks so. But it&amp;rsquo;s ok for a name of software, I don&amp;rsquo;t care about too much what it called.  FireFox is cool name, everyone know it.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;strong>Crash Continually&lt;/strong>: It proved Chrome browser is on early stage. For me, I won&amp;rsquo;t any software on my laptop send out any piece of information which I don&amp;rsquo;t know or couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand. So, I will never  turn on crash report option for any software. It is still crashing frequently, I might will not use it any more; or install it.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->**Bookmark on top: **My laptop has supper wide screen, so all of bookmarks are listing on the left side of Firefox/IE. I like to access bookmark from left side of screen. It is on the top and just below the address bar, I have to close it.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;strong>ADs in Gmail/anywhere it could be:&lt;/strong> In Firefox, I get really few AD showed up. Nobody love ADs, but Google can not do with our AD.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;strong>Without Add-ons:&lt;/strong> It is so important for extending the usage of your browser. Add-on makes a browser to do more jobs as you wash for. I can list some add-ons of Firefox, they are very helpful and I must have all of them.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->I thinks Google really good at marketing. it crashed into browser marketing, its ambition knows no limits. All in all, Chrome is not a good enough to be my default browser; Fixfox will keeping do this job for me. Chrome is a ok software, it is no offence to Googl&amp;rsquo;s fans.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>