<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bladelogic on Martin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://martinliu.cn/tags/bladelogic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bladelogic on Martin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <managingEditor>liuzh66@gmail.com (刘征 Martin Liu)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>liuzh66@gmail.com (刘征 Martin Liu)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:52:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://martinliu.cn/tags/bladelogic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>M$ Windows is eating your hard driver</title>
      <link>https://martinliu.cn/2008/10/24/ms-windows-is-eating-your-hard-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>liuzh66@gmail.com (刘征 Martin Liu)</author>
      <guid>https://martinliu.cn/2008/10/24/ms-windows-is-eating-your-hard-driver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://lh5.ggpht.com/liuzh66/SQEZ0RBOw_I/AAAAAAAAA38/Ulq2AKwYejU/s800/Access%20is%20denied.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;No matter Bill says how friendly M$ Windows is. It is eating more and more my free disk space. Toady I figured out some tips for releasing disk space. In Windows file explore, you can not see the folder size without checking on property. So you may need a tool, something like FolderSizes. FolderSize helps me to know more about my heard diver. It shows me there is a folder &amp;lsquo;System Volume information&amp;rdquo;, this folder is 6.20GB big. What the hell is that??? I can not even see it in file explore. Then I check on Folder Options, here are so many hiding options for you. In order to take out that big folder, I unchecked &amp;lsquo;&amp;ldquo;Hide protected operating system files and folders&amp;rdquo;, then the folder shows up. But I can not open it sine I really wants to know what hell is been hidden in that folder. A error message box popup up&amp;rdquo;Assess is denied.&amp;rdquo; WOW this is my laptop, I am not able to access the folder. Is this a M$ asset? In FolderSize, I can go inside this folder; it has so many files. Everything in this folder looks like patch file. I have no idea where and when it went down my computer; or this dame OS made it. Now I&amp;rsquo;m deleting these files and folders in folder &amp;lsquo;System Volume information&amp;rdquo; from FolderSize. Another error message box popup up; it says &amp;ldquo;Cannot delete XXX000.ps1: It is being used by another person or program&amp;rdquo;. Kidding me? Does anyone share this laptop with me at this moment? Fortunately I have openSuSe, I issued rm -rf command after booted into openSuse. Now 6.2GB space was released.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>