<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>服务建模 on Martin Liu's Blog</title><link>https://martinliu.cn/tags/%E6%9C%8D%E5%8A%A1%E5%BB%BA%E6%A8%A1/</link><description>Recent content in 服务建模 on Martin Liu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 01:17:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martinliu.cn/tags/%E6%9C%8D%E5%8A%A1%E5%BB%BA%E6%A8%A1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>图书推荐《服务建模：原理与应用》</title><link>https://martinliu.cn/2011/02/12/book-service-modelling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 01:17:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinliu.cn/2011/02/12/book-service-modelling/</guid><description>&lt;p>《服务建模: 原理与应用》以服务建模为主题，共分 4 部分：第 1 部分介绍了服务建模所需解决的问题，第 2 部分分析了实际应用中的服务建模框架，第 3 部分列举了使用服务建模的案例，第 4 部分则对《服务建模:原理与应用》的中心内容进行了总结，并提出了未来服务建模值得研究的一些领域。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Learn how to use service modelling to streamline and optimize processes!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Information about customer needs, the technical composition of services, and service performance are fundamental to effective service management.  Service modelling is a structured approach to utilizing this information to improve the way services are delivered.  Consistent application of service modelling provides the automation of processes and timely access to information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_50942&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;201&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Service Modelling: Principles and Applications &amp;ldquo;]&lt;img src="http://7bv9gn.com1.z0.glb.clouddn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/couverture_OKLWOOARSOLOWB-201x300.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="Service Modelling: Principles and Applications "
>](&lt;a class="link" href="http://martinliu.cn/2011/02/book-service-modelling.html/couverture_oklwooarsolowb%29[/caption]" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://martinliu.cn/2011/02/book-service-modelling.html/couverture_oklwooarsolowb)[/caption]&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Service Modelling&lt;/em> presents a comprehensive, up-to-date overview of the topic, presented in the context both of business processes, and of requirements stemming from the need to manage network resources. Vilho Räisänen delivers a justification for service modelling, and explains state-of-the-art concepts, frameworks and standards in detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Service Modelling:&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Provides a complete and illustrated overview of state-of-the-art concepts for service modelling, covering requirements and frameworks.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Includes industry initiatives, conceptual frameworks, and the work of standardisation bodies.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Discusses different modelling approaches, and the positioning of modelling of services in service management and in the wider operational context.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sets the modelling framework in the context of business drivers and modelling paradigms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Illustrates principles with real-world use cases, providing both fixed Internet and mobile network examples.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Relates concepts to the work of TeleManagement Forum, giving practical examples throughout.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Service Modelling: Principles and Applications&lt;/em> is an invaluable guide to service modelling for telecommunications and data communications professionals, including vendors, operators, consultants, training organizations, service and content providers, system architects and engineers for IP-based services.  Educational organizations, advanced undergraduate and graduate students on telecommunications and networking courses will also find this text invaluable.&lt;img src="http://ec4.images-amazon.com/images/I/41pNX5HatCL._SL500_AA240_.jpg"
loading="lazy"
alt="服务建模图书"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>本书的已经翻译为中文版本，本书中包含了针对电信行业的实例模型和介绍，图书内容介绍如下：&lt;/p>
&lt;p>《服务建模:原理与应用》主要内容简介：服务技术的发展，不仅彻底改变了人们原有的生活方式，更从本质上促进了当代社会经济发展方式的转变。《服务建模: 原理与应用》以服务建模为主题，共分 4 部分：第 1 部分介绍了服务建模所需解决的问题，第 2 部分分析了实际应用中的服务建模框架，第 3 部分列举了使用服务建模的案例，第 4 部分则对《服务建模:原理与应用》的中心内容进行了总结，并提出了未来服务建模值得研究的一些领域。
《服务建模:原理与应用》可作为高校信息技术、管理和经济类相关学科电子服务方向的教学用书。也可以作为现代服务企业进行服务建模方面研究的工具书或参考书。&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>