<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FolderSize on Martin Liu's Blog</title><link>https://martinliu.cn/tags/foldersize/</link><description>Recent content in FolderSize on Martin Liu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-cn</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:52:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martinliu.cn/tags/foldersize/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>M$ Windows is eating your hard driver</title><link>https://martinliu.cn/2008/10/24/ms-windows-is-eating-your-hard-driver/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:52:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://martinliu.cn/2008/10/24/ms-windows-is-eating-your-hard-driver/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/liuzh66/SQEZ0RBOw_I/AAAAAAAAA38/Ulq2AKwYejU/s800/Access%20is%20denied.jpg"
loading="lazy"
>No matter Bill says how friendly M$ Windows is. It is eating more and more my free disk space. Toady I figured out some tips for releasing disk space. In Windows file explore, you can not see the folder size without checking on property. So you may need a tool, something like FolderSizes. FolderSize helps me to know more about my heard diver. It shows me there is a folder &amp;lsquo;System Volume information&amp;quot;, this folder is 6.20GB big. What the hell is that??? I can not even see it in file explore. Then I check on Folder Options, here are so many hiding options for you. In order to take out that big folder, I unchecked &amp;lsquo;&amp;ldquo;Hide protected operating system files and folders&amp;rdquo;, then the folder shows up. But I can not open it sine I really wants to know what hell is been hidden in that folder. A error message box popup up&amp;quot;Assess is denied.&amp;quot; WOW this is my laptop, I am not able to access the folder. Is this a M$ asset? In FolderSize, I can go inside this folder; it has so many files. Everything in this folder looks like patch file. I have no idea where and when it went down my computer; or this dame OS made it. Now I&amp;rsquo;m deleting these files and folders in folder &amp;lsquo;System Volume information&amp;quot; from FolderSize. Another error message box popup up; it says &amp;ldquo;Cannot delete XXX000.ps1: It is being used by another person or program&amp;rdquo;. Kidding me? Does anyone share this laptop with me at this moment? Fortunately I have openSuSe, I issued rm -rf command after booted into openSuse. Now 6.2GB space was released.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Within FolderSize, one more fat folder was identified out, It is &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;C:\Documents and Settings\LocalService\Local Settings\Application Data\Google&amp;rsquo;. I have Google Desktop on my laptop, but I did not use Google desktop search too much, but it take me near 2GBs space. I realized Google desktop indexed my whole hard drive anyway. I have to uninstalled Google Desktop and deleted that folder. Now I got more 2GB space.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->M$ Windows also did anther favorite for me to created a fat pagefile.sys. It is 3.5 GB; Big~~ isn&amp;rsquo;t it? My laptop have 4GBs physical RAM, but XP only use 3.5GB. As same 32bit OS, openSuSE does use all of 4GB. Since I am short of free space, pagefile.sys was changed to 1.5GB. SO, 2GB spaces was saved.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->In XP file system, there are some files can not be deleted. I bet you do have some files like that. Those files are already useless, but you can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of them. &lt;a class="link" href="http://www.threatexpert.com/files/ForceDel.exe.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>ForceDel.exe&lt;/a> can delete them all. This tiny tool saved me more then 1GB space.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->6.2+2+2+1=11.2GB&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->There are more screen-shots, please check out: &lt;a class="link" href="http://picasaweb.google.com/liuzh66/Mis" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://picasaweb.google.com/liuzh66/Mis&lt;/a> and comment.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Ok now I&amp;rsquo;m be able to create at least two VMWare machines for my work. I hope those tips are helpful for you.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->In this week, I&amp;rsquo;m so busy on a Bladelogic product POC testing for CCB which is one of the biggest bank in China. At evening, I usually had to study on ITIL v3 stuff in order to get myself ready for a upcoming training next month. But tonight I&amp;rsquo;d like to take time off of the work.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;strong>XP 磁盘空间节省偏方&lt;/strong>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item></channel></rss>